We use cookies and other tools to enhance your experience on our website and to analyze our web traffic. For more information about these cookies and the data collected, please refer to our [**privacy policy.**](https://www.childrensal.org/childrens-alabama-online-privacy-policy)

Close

[205-638-9100](tel:2056389100 "Click to call 205-638-9100") [Close](javascript:void(0); "Close")

* [Locations](https://www.childrensal.org/locations)[](javascript:void(0) "Expand menu")
* [Patients & Visitors](https://www.childrensal.org/patients-visitors)[](javascript:void(0) "Expand menu")
* Ways to Give[](javascript:void(0) "Expand menu")

### Locations

### Patients & Visitors

### Ways to Give

* [Locations](javascript:void(0);)
* [Patients & Visitors](javascript:void(0);)
* [Ways to Give](javascript:void(0);)

[search](javascript:void(0); "Click to search") [show off canvas menu](javascript:void(0);)

1. [Home](https://www.childrensal.org/)
2. Children's of Alabama Online Privacy Policy

Children's of Alabama Online Privacy Policy
===========================================

* * *

Children’s of Alabama (“Children’s”) is committed to protecting privacy regarding the use of its website ([www.childrensal.org](https://www.childrensal.org/ "Children's of Alabama")), its different social media platforms, and related applications.

**About Your Information/Data We Are Processing**

Children’s does not collect identifying information about you (such as your name, address telephone number, health information, insurance information, credit card information, or email address), unless you voluntarily submit that information to us.  This includes, but is not limited to, information such as comments, payments for patient care services, granting donations, sending job or volunteer inquiries, ordering logo merchandise, or requesting newsletters. The type of information we collect depends on the website or application you may be using and the information you choose to share with us.

Children’s may use “cookies” to facilitate the “access to” and “usage of” our websites.  The intent is to provide a more user-friendly or customized website experience.  We do not use cookies to collect data for future contact outside the realm of our websites or applications. Most web browsers offer instructions on how to reset the browser to reject cookies in the “Help” section of the toolbar. You do not have to accept cookies in order to use our website or applications.

**How We Use Information/How We Process Data Collected**

The information you submit and collected by Children’s is gathered and stored by us on various media. Depending on the type of information, that information may be shared with our third-party vendors to further “The Purpose for Processing Data” (see below).

**The Purpose for Processing Data/Why We Collect Data**

Depending on the information collected, we may use the information for some of the following:

* We may share information with our service providers, including for example, a shipping company or credit card processing company, for products ordered through our online gift shop;
* To further the purpose for which you provide information;
* To communicate directly with you; 
* To improve our website or applications, including fixing errors or “bugs”; 
* To improve our patient/family experiences and interactions;

Children’s reserves the right to disclose any information in its possession if it is required to do so by law or if we believe in good faith that such a disclosure is necessary to comply with the law, defend its rights or property, or to respond to an emergency situation. 

Children’s does not sell, share, or rent out the information we collect to third parties. 

**Your Right to Request Deletion or Correction of Data**

Residents of the European Union may exercise certain data subject rights available to them under applicable data protection laws. Where such rights apply, we will comply with requests to exercise these rights in accordance with applicable laws. Please note that certain information may be exempt from such requests, for example, if we are required to retain processing information for our legitimate interests or to comply with legal obligations. Accordingly, you may have the right to request some of the following:

* That we update personal information which is out of date or incorrect;
* That we delete certain personal information which we have collected about you; 
* That we restrict the way we process and disclose specific personal information about you; 
* That we transfer your personal information to a third-party provider of services;

If you are requesting to exercise some other right with respect to your data, please contact us through the “Contact Us” information below.

**Security**

Children’s utilizes reasonable security measures to protect the personal information you submit to us.  Such security includes the use of SSL-secured web forms, firewalls, and other commonly-employed security methods. However, due to the nature of the internet, Children’s is unable to guarantee complete security of its website or applications. 

**Other Sites**

Children’s privacy policy applies only to your use of our website and applications. Children’s is not responsible for the privacy practices of sites linked to the Children’s website. You should read the privacy policy of each site you visit to determine what information that site may be collecting about you. 

**User Submissions**

Children’s welcomes your comments on its content and the information contained herein. You understand you do so at your own choice. However, you acknowledge that if you send Children’s or its related sites and applications creative suggestions, ideas, notes, drawings, concepts, inventions, or other information, the information shall be deemed and shall remain the property of Children’s. By submitting any information to us, unless explicitly stated otherwise, you assign to us and we shall exclusively own all known or hereafter existing rights to such information and shall be entitled to unrestricted use of the information for any purpose whatsoever, commercial or otherwise, without compensation to you. 

**Appropriate Use**

You are responsible for complying with the law and the terms and conditions of our website and related applications. You are responsible if you violate the terms and conditions of our website and related applications. While we endeavor to monitor the content of our website, social media platforms, and applications, Children’s is not responsible for constantly monitoring all content. Children’s reserves the right to expel users and to prevent further access to this site for violating these terms or the law and reserves the right to remove any communications from its sites, applications, or platforms. The violation of any of the terms and conditions set forth on the Terms and Conditions page shall result in the immediate revocation of your right to use our content. 

**A Note to Parents**

You are responsible to supervise your child on this website to make sure they are utilizing this website according to your wishes. If Children’s discovers that data we have collected is personal information under applicable law from a child under the age of 16 without legally-valid parental consent, we will take reasonable steps to remove it. 

**Changes to Our Privacy and Security Policies**

Just as with the other terms and conditions of our website and applications, Children’s may change the terms and conditions of our Online Privacy Policy at any time without notice to you by posting revisions to those site, platforms, or applications. By accessing or using those platforms, sites, or applications, you agree to be bound by all of the terms and conditions. 

**Contact Information**

Questions about this privacy policy may be directed to: 

Kathleen Street  
Privacy Officer   
Children’s of Alabama   
1600 7th Avenue South  
Birmingham, AL 35233  
Email: [HIPAA@ChildrensAL.org](mailto:HIPAA@ChildrensAL.org)  
Phone: 205.638.5959  
Fax: 205.638.2857

Questions regarding fundraising activities, may be directed to: 

Stefanie Blakely  
Phone: 205.638.2769  
Fax: 205-638-2743

(Updated February 9, 2023)  

##### **I WANT TO...**

##### **PATIENTS**

[Request Medical Records (PDF)- English](https://www.childrensal.org/sites/default/files/2023-08/Authorization_for_Release_of_Information_764_Eng.pdf "Request Medical Records (PDF) English")

[Request Medical Records (PDF)- Spanish](https://www.childrensal.org/sites/default/files/2023-08/Authorization_for_Release_of_Information_764_Sp.pdf "Request Medical Records (PDF)")

Health and Safety Tips

##### **PHYSICIANS**

[ACE Opportunities](https://www.childrensal.org/services/healthcare-professionals/ace-accredited-continuing-education-opportunities "ACE (Accredited Continuing Education) Opportunities")

##### **MEDIA**

##### **AWARDS & RECOGNITION**

##### **CONNECT**

​​​​​[Parents](http://kidshealth.org/ChildrensAlabama/en/parents "KidsHealth: Parents") [Teens](http://kidshealth.org/ChildrensAlabama/en/teens "KidsHealth:Teens") [Kids](http://kidshealth.org/ChildrensAlabama/en/kids "KidsHealth:Kids") [](http://kidshealth.org/ChildrensAlabama/en/)

© 2023 Children's of Alabama | 1600 7th Ave. S. | Birmingham AL 35233 | [205-638-9100](tel: 205-638-9100)
